agisoft.com 2019-12-10

# PRIVACY POLICY Agisoft LLC

PRIVACY POLICY
Agisoft LLC (hereinafter Agisoft) has created this Privacy Policy to explain to you clearly
and conclusively how Agisoft processes (including collection, use, transferring, storage,
deletion, etc.) your personal information. The Privacy Policy informs you of your rights as a
data subject. The Privacy Policy is an integral part of the agreements between you and
Agisoft.
Agisoft processes personal data in accordance with applicable law, including consistent with
the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April
2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and
on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/446/EC (the Regulation).
If you purchase Agisoft’s products as a natural person, Agisoft is the controller of your
personal data. If a legal entity purchases Agisoft’s products, Agisoft acts as a processor of
the collected data (contact person’s name, contact details, etc.). Please read the Privacy
Policy carefully prior to submitting the data and use of Agisoft’s products or services (the
Software).
1.   What kind of personal data does Agisoft collect?
2.   How does Agisoft collect the personal data?
3.   What are the purposes of the processing?
4.   Where we store and process personal data?
5.   How long do we retain your personal data?
6.   To whom and why we transfer your personal data?
7.   Does Agisoft use cookies?
8.   What are your rights as a data subject?
If you cannot find the answers you're looking for in our Privacy Policy or have any other
questions regarding your personal data, please do not hesitate to contact Agisoft using the
following contact information:
Name:           Agisoft LLC
                11 Degtyarniy per.,
Address:        St. Petersburg,
                Russia, 191144
E-mail:         info@agisoft.com
Website:        http://www.agisoft.com/about/

1.  What kind of personal data does Agisoft collect?
    ● Basic identification data: First and last name;
    ● Contact data: E-mail address, mobile number, mailing address;
    ● If you represent a legal entity, information about the entity you represent;
    ● Product related information: Trial and purchase history, unique licence numbers;
    ● Last four digits of the credit card number;
   ● Software error related data: last rows from a log file of Software (auxiliary information
       on operations), system configuration information (CPU, GPU, RAM, OS version,
       drivers’ version), serial number of the hard disk or MAC-address.
   ● Information that you provide in Agisoft’s online forum.
2. How does Agisoft collect the personal data?
We collect your data when:
    ● you order Software via our website (hereinafter Website), by telephone, email or mail;
    ● you order Software from our resellers and the resellers forward your data to Agisoft.
    ● you request information about Software by telephone, email or mail;
    ● a Software error occurs (e.g. Software crashes) and you choose to send the error
       related data to Agisoft.
3.  What are the purposes of the processing?
   Agisoft is developing stand-alone software (such as Agisoft Metashape). In order to
   licence the software and/or use related services, you have to conclude a contract with
   Agisoft. Therefore, Agisoft processes your personal data for the performance of the
   contract and in order to take steps prior to entering into a contract. Agisoft collects your
   identification data, contact data, product related information and payment details in order
   to provide you the software and related services (for example customer support).
    Furthermore, the processing might be necessary for compliance with legal obligations to
    which Agisoft is subject. For example, Agisoft is required to organise the accounting and
    financial reporting.
    Agisoft will also process your personal data if the processing is necessary for the
    purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Agisoft. In every such case Agisoft will
    consider whether such interests might be overridden by the interests or fundamental
    rights and freedoms of you as a data subject. For example, Agisoft has the legitimate
    interest to process your data to help with fraud identification and prevention.
    Agisoft can process your personal data if you have given consent to the processing of
    your personal data for one or more specific purposes. For example, you can choose
    whether you send to Agisoft the Software error related data or not. You have the right to
    withdraw your consent at any time. However, we remind you that the withdrawal of
    consent does not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its
    withdrawal.
4.  Where we store and process personal data?
    Agisoft’s headquarters are located in 11 Degtyarniy per., St. Petersburg, Russia. Agisoft
    retains most of the data on a password protected server on local network (no access
    from Internet). When the data is transferred to us, we implement appropriate safeguards
    and means. We place great importance on the security of all personally identifiable
    information associated with our users. We have security measures in place to attempt to
    protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control.
    We always will carefully assess all the circumstances and make sure appropriate

   safeguards are put in place so that your rights are not in any way undermined. We make
   sure that conditions to enforce your rights and effective legal remedies are available.
   Agisoft may use data processors and in such case some of the data may be stored in
   their servers. Agisoft uses only processors providing sufficient guarantees to implement
   appropriate technical and organisational measures in such a manner that processing will
   meet the requirements of this Policy and ensure the protection of the rights of the data
   subject. For example, if you use our cloud processing service, your data will be stored in
   Amazon’s servers (you can review Amazon Web Services’ Privacy Policy here). If you
   use customer support, all related information is stored by Freshworks Inc (you can
   review Freshworks Privacy Policy here). Please also see Section 6 of the Policy for more
   information about processors. If you need more detailed information about processing by
   processors carried out on behalf of Agisoft, please contact us.
5. How long do we retain your personal data?
   Agisoft has both the right and the obligation to retain the personal data collected for a
   period of time. Agisoft does not retain personal information longer than necessary to
   achieve the purposes of processing and comply with the obligations of Agisoft. However,
   Agisoft may retain the personal data for a longer period of time if you have given consent
   for longer storage and processing of the data.
   Agisoft’s Software licenses are not time-limited. Therefore, Agisoft will keep your
   personal information data that is related to the license (name, contact details, licence
   number, etc.) as long as the licence is valid.
   The license also includes 12 month of e-mail based technical support. In practice Agisoft
   continues to support its users after the guaranteed support period as well. However,
   Agisoft reserves the right to review its support policy with respect to the after-one-year
   period at its sole discretion without prior notice to the user. As a general rule Agisoft will
   retain the data collected during support period until the user contacts Agisoft via e-mail
   with request to erase their data.
   If Agisoft sends personal information to another controller, the data retention periods are
   determined by the recipient of the data.
6. To whom and why we transfer your personal data?
   Agisoft discloses personal information only to the extent and in the form necessary for
   the fulfilment of the purposes listed in the Privacy Policy.
   Agisoft may transfer your personal data to other data controllers or processors. Agisoft
   may share information with companies that provide support services to Agisoft (for
   example BrightMarket LLC dba FastSpring – online shop; Freshworks Inc, Freshdesk –
   support desk system; Yandex LLC – Yandex.Mail e-mail accounts, Infobox – web site
   hosting (forum with its user database)). These companies may need information about
   you in order to perform their functions. Data processors are not authorized to use the
   shared data for any other purpose.
   Agisoft transfers personal data if Agisoft is legally bound by such an obligation. For
   example, Agisoft might be obligated to disclose personal data to public authorities upon
   their legitimate request.
7. Does Agisoft use cookies?
   We use first-party cookies to track your interactions on the Website. Agisoft’s Website
   uses Google Analytics. You can read more about Google Analytics’ data practices’ here.

     We use the cookies to accumulate general statistics data about web-site pages
     information relevance.
     It is prohibited to send Personally Identifiable Information (Google interprets PII as
     information that could be used on its own to directly identify, contact, or precisely locate
     an individual) to Google Analytics. Therefore, we do not collect any personal data with
     the cookies.
     However, if you still wish to opt-out, you may disable cookies or delete any individual
     cookie. You can download the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on here.
8.   What are your rights as a data subject?
     You have the right to receive information about the personal data processed by Agisoft,
     including the categories of data processed, the sources of the data, purposes of
     processing etc. You are also entitled to receive copies and extracts of personal data
     processed. You have the right to request the correction or updating of data if it turns out
     that the personal data being processed is inaccurate.
     You have the right on to object to processing, on grounds relating to your particular
     situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you if such processing is
     only necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Agisoft.
     You have the right to obtain from Agisoft restriction of processing or the erasure of your
     personal data Agisoft will erase your data or implement other measures that result in the
     data becoming permanently anonymous if:
          ●  your personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which
             they were collected or otherwise processed;
          ●  you withdraw the consent on which the processing is based and there is no other
             legal ground for the processing;
          ●  you object to the processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for
             the processing;
          ●  your personal data have been unlawfully processed;
          ●  your personal data have to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation to
             which Agisoft is subject.
     Agisoft will fulfil your request within a reasonable time, but no later than one month after
     receiving the request.
     In case of any suspected infringement of your privacy, please contact us. We’ll try to
     resolve the dispute by negotiation. However, you also have the right to lodge a complaint
     to the supervisory authority (without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial
     remedy). In European Union every data subject has the right to lodge the complaint in
     the Member State of his or her habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged
     infringement if the data subject considers that the processing of personal data relating to
     him or her infringes the Regulation.
Any revisions to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the Agisoft Website. We recommend to
periodically visit our Website to review any changes that may be made to this Privacy Policy.
If you continue to use our Website and services, it constitutes your agreement to be bound
by this Privacy Policy and any possible changes.
This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25 March 2019.
